https://www.uaccb.edu/pages/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
UACCB Operating Procedure  Procedure 925.1Website Privacy Policy   I.          Overview:This policy defines the privacy policy for official websites of the University of Arkansas Community College at Batesville (UACCB), addresses collection and use of information in connection with such websites, and describes under what circumstances the college may disclose such information, consistent with Ark. Code § 25-1-114.II.         Practice:1) Official University WebsitesExcept as noted otherwise, the information in this privacy policy applies to all official UACCB websites, which are defined as those administered through the college content management system, such as main departments, divisions, or other units typically reporting to or deemed official by the chancellor, vice chancellors, directors and/or department heads/chairs. These sites comply with the college template, graphics and Web standards as managed by the Communications and Marketing Department and the Information Services Department. Certain official websites may have their own or supplementary privacy policies appropriate to their function or as required by law.2) Information CollectedUACCB, while reserving the right to monitor communications via its websites for legal, policy or business reasons, including security and functionality, does not monitor the content of communications as a matter of normal business practice. However, the fact that communication occurred (such as when a user visits a UACCB website or utilizes UACCB websites to search for information or submit a form), may be routinely logged as a normal business practice. Common information logged through interaction with UACCB websites includes, but is not limited to, the following:the IP address of the user’s computer;the date and time a user’s computer accessed our site;the IP address and URL of a referring website;the page the user requested from the site; the information that a user’s Web browser software sends, which typically identifies the browser software and may also indicate the operating system and type of CPU used in the user’s computer; in the case of email, the sender and recipient's email addresses; andin the case of services provided to you through UACCB websites via forms (e.g., admissions, financial aid requests, job applications), surveys, course-work, etc., personal information you provide in order to process the request, such as name, physical and email addresses, phone numbers, and financial data may be collected and may be retained - if information requested is not entered, the services and/or requests cannot be accomplished online.UACCB collects no personal information about visitors to the college’s websites, unless visitors voluntarily make such information available. Information such as the internet domain and IP address from which a visitor accesses the site is automatically recognized by a server. This information does not result in the identification of personal email addresses or any other personal information.3) Google AnalyticsThe host of some  UACCB websites uses Google Analytics, a Web analytics service provided by Google, Inc., to collect information such as URLs, Internet domain and host names, browser software and date and time site visited.  Google Analytics maintains its own privacy policy, which may be reviewed at https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites.4) CookiesUACCB or its website vendors may use cookies to provide the user with tailored information from a website or to collect usage statistics.  A cookie is an element of data that a website can send to a browser, which may then store it on the user’s system.  Some applications may require the user to accept cookies in order for the application to work properly. Two types of cookies exist, session cookies and persistent cookies. Session cookies contain data through which the Web application the visitor is using can maintain the continuity and state of a session. Session cookies expire upon user logout, closing of the browser or timed-out sessions. Persistent cookies contain information that may be useful across multiple sessions, such as identifying the user or other persistent attributes, and are typically not deleted. Data from cookies may also be used to identify user trends and patterns, provide services and record session information. Web browsers can be configured to refuse cookies, accept cookies, disable cookies and remove cookies as needed or desired. In most cases, a visitor can refuse a cookie and still fully navigate the site.5) How Personal Data Is UsedAs a general rule, UACCB does not track individual visitor profiles. Data that is collected through the UACCB websites may be used to analyze aggregate traffic/access information for resource management, site planning, advertising and marketing. In addition, UACCB monitors the volume and timing of access to the site by collecting information on the date, time, and pages accessed by visitors. The information collected is used to better understand general site usage patterns, improve site usability, and improve the content of the site. None of this information is shared with other organizations or tied to any individual user.Information obtained by UACCB websites is used only for the intended purpose stated when the information is collected. Data is not used for secondary or unrelated purposes, or shared with a third party, unless otherwise disclosed at the point of collection. If information is to be shared with third parties, visitors will be asked for permission beforehand.  Some of the information voluntarily provided by visitors through email messages or completing an online form may be saved for a designated period to comply with Arkansas’ archiving policies.UACCB  may also use information gathered through its websites  or exchange such information with other entities in order to carry out normal UACCB business operations, including marketing and subcontractor services.  Legal requirements concerning use and disclosure of sensitive information will be applied to information maintained with these resources to the same extent that the requirements are applied to other records kept or maintained by UACCB. The college does not sell, rent, loan, trade, or lease any personal information collected on our site. 6) Third Party Applications and LinksUACCB websites contains links to third party applications and websites that are not official UACCB websites that may or may not be hosted by or on behalf of UACCB. UACCB  cannot warrant or be responsible for the privacy policies or content of such sites. Users are encouraged to become familiar with the privacy policies of third party or off-campus sites.7) SecurityIn addition to complying with all applicable laws and regulations, UACCB strives to implement and maintain systems and policies to protect the confidentiality and integrity of personal information provided by users.  Despite these security measures, the college does not represent or warrant that personal information will be protected against loss, misuse or alteration by third parties.8) Required Disclosure of Data CollectedThe college is required to comply with the Arkansas Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) (Ark. Code Ann. § 25-19-101 et seq.) and may be required to disclose records maintained in the daily operations of the college unless such records are exempt from disclosure under federal or state law. Therefore, some data collected through UACCB websites may be subject to disclosure upon receipt of a valid FOIA request.Additionally, at times, the college may be legally required to disclose information collected through UACCB websites in response to a valid subpoena or court order or to comply with a legally permitted inquiry by a governmental agency or regulatory body.Subject to governing law and other applicable university policies, the college reserves the right to disclose information collected on its websites to governmental authorities in connection with suspected unlawful activity or to aid an investigation into suspected unlawful activity. In addition, the college reserves the right to release information collected on UACCB websites to appropriate governmental authorities if college officials determine, in their sole judgment, that UACCB policies have been violated, or that release of information is necessary to protect the rights, health, safety or property of persons or the college or to protect the integrity of UACCB computer networks. Further, the college reserves the right to disclose information as college officials believe necessary to exercise the college’s legal rights, to defend against actual or potential legal claims, or as otherwise permitted or required by UACCB or University of Arkansas System policies. III.       QuestionsFor more information regarding this policy, please contact the Department of Communications and Marketing at 870-612-2145 or email hannah.keller@uaccb.edu.The college’s human-readable privacy policy is located at the following address: www.uaccb.edu//privacy-policy/Adopted:            December 18, 2019Click here to download a PDF of the privacy policy.
Apply Now
And Start Your UACCB Journey Today
Apply Now
My UACCB
Take A Tour
Enroll Now
HOME
GETTING STARTED
Click HERE for information about UACCB's return to campus for the fall 2020 semester. View COVID-19 updates HERE.
